<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Moore&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Daniel Moore&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://danielpygo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking up</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/love/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s nothing worse than a relationship on its last leg and that&amp;rsquo;s kind of where I have been for the last 3 months. It was miserable, but last night I felt like a weight was lifted off me and that I could finally breathe easy again. With so many rules, forbidden topics, and arguments/accusations, it was starting to feel like an adverserial game . Like, we weren&amp;rsquo;t on the same team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/programming/evolutionary-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/programming/evolutionary-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Last night, for my neural networks class, we were told to make Tux (basically mario but a penguin) complete all the levels using a gradient free method. It was interesting because it was fine tuning a model that was able to get decently far into the level.  In my previous model I used convolutional neural network to feed into the features of a GRU Recurrent network. Then, without needing backprop, I trained 20 models using some small deviation on the parameters, and generated rewards for each of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 01:19:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/about/about/</guid>
      <description>Currently, I am a student at The University of Texas at Austin and am majoring in Computer Science. My expertise is in Cloud Computing and Software Engineering (Applications/Backend). I am excellent at C++, Java and Go. I have done a lot of coding in Python as well for artificial intelligence related courses  I am a software engineer attending UT Austin, and am good at systems, applications, and cloud computing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complexity: What Excites Me</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/thegame/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 23:49:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/thegame/</guid>
      <description>The Game Begat the Player  With any discipline, challenge, or complexity - a difficult game always excites the clever player who tries to bend the rules in his favor. It&#39;s cat and mouse game where people try to gain a competitive advantage over one and other . The ingenuinity and creativity of hackers, startups, poker players and of people in dating, politics and gaming, always impresses me. People push things forward for its own sake - it&#39;s just fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume - Seeking Full Time Software Engineering Role or Summer Internship</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/resume/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 21:24:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/resume/resume/</guid>
      <description>I am applying for both right now! If I get the internship I want, I would take another semester to finish my minor after it in December 2019 (Since internships require a semester after it ends). As of right now, I am set to graduate in May 2019.   Download pdf!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hashing</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/hashing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 20:55:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/hashing/</guid>
      <description>Cmu hashing notes
Separate Chaining  The idea is to maintain an array of linked lists All keys that hash to the same loc are just added to the linked list. Could maybe optimize these linked lists by having an lru cache implemntation or another data structure .. Cost of these operations is related to the average len of a chain. Disadvantage - costly allocation, and memory for the pointers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ray Tracing/Physics</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/light_physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 20:55:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/light_physics/</guid>
      <description>Mirrors
Why do mirrors reflect: Nature of the metal  Electrons are loosely attached to metals and are able to For visible light (low frequency), the electrons can match the speed and reflect the light. For UV, it is too high so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t reflect
 Different metals reflect different wavelengths The highest frequency light reflected is called plasma frequency
 This differs between metals, steel is high
  &amp;ldquo;Mirrors reflect mainly bc they are electrically conductive&amp;rdquo;  When it hits a mirror the metal cancels out the electric field parallel to the mirror, so it changes directions and reflects away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 15:55:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>What I hope to get out of this blog, is a central store for my life, career and interests. Some may not care much about my career, so I intend to have other content on here as well. I have created two blogs in the past on wordpress, but they haven&amp;rsquo;t really given me what I wanted  Putting my thoughts and projects out there seems like a cool way to connect with people!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Closer Look into the Big-Four</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/closerlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/closerlook/</guid>
      <description>Intro  As a soon-to-be new grad, I am currently preparing for interviews with Google and Microsoft so I want to dive deeper into Microsoft, Google, Amazon, and Facebook.  I read the go-to book on investing and the history of the stock market about three years ago and have identified myself as a risky investor . Nothing ventured nothing gained right? His advice is that the best you can ever do is to just throw your hands up in resignment and throw your money in an low-cost index fund; he&#39;s probably right but I like taking a risk and putting my money in companies I believe in  Hypothetically, If I had to put all my money into one company and hold it for 3 years who would I choose?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Year plan</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/future/</guid>
      <description>In 5 years I see myself working for a large tech company like Amazon/Google/Microsoft and building my skills to become an integral and useful developer. I have found that I get happiness when I see personal growth and by being ambitious/useful.  I plan on getting a few certificates and eventually doing an online masters program in the next 5 years. Building my github portfolio more is something I want to do more out of college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Be a Hater</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/judging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/judging/</guid>
      <description>I watched a Vice documentary on an infamous character in American culture, and it was one of those moments where you realize you had been totally wrong about someone. The editing and narrative by Vice, was obviously trying to show a different perspective on this guy, and by the end of it the reporter seemed charmed with him and maaaybbeee had a crush on him as well
One of the top YouTube comments was &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s like someone from twitch chat became a millionaire&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re: Exit Through The Gift Shop</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/banksy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/banksy/</guid>
      <description>I just watched Exit Through The Gift Shop (2010) the other night and it has to be my favorite documentary. It&#39;s about graffiti art and produced by Banksy. It&#39;s a documentary started by a crazy but hilarious french graffiti cameraman Thierry, but eventually finished by Banksy, the most famous and unmasked graffiti artist alive. Thierry, the cameraman, could never finish because he had collected thousands of hours of film over 8 years, with no real plan or storyline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/programming/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/programming/intro/</guid>
      <description> This will be a blog about things I am programming, opinions on programming languages, algorithms/projects that inspire me, and my classes as a CS undergrad at UT Austin! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threads and Processes</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/threadsprocess/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/threadsprocess/</guid>
      <description>Process is an executing program
A process can consist of multiple threads
Threads are lightweight processes used to complete small tasks; processes used for heavier tasks.
Advantages of Threads:  Lightweight Can read and write to the same data structures and resources.  Disadvantages of Threads:  IPC is difficult and errors arise Synchronization and race conditions Requires careful attention; must use a lock to prevent other threads from running a certain critical section  Advantages of Process  Independent of each other (threads are interdepedent)  Context Switching  The process of storing an d restoring context of a program so that the exectuion can be resumed from the same point at another time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>