<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Moore&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Daniel Moore&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://danielpygo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Nights Short Mornings is actually a good movie</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/longnightsshortmornings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/longnightsshortmornings/</guid>
      <description>You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t think that from glancing at the imdb page, where it has a rating of 5.4&amp;frasl;10, but watching it again last night, it finally resonated with me.
I think that I watched it with my now, ex-girlfriend about a year and a half ago. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been paying close attention, and watching a movie with someone else is always a bit distracting for me. And so I came away with it empty handed and just lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hitchens</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/hitchens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/hitchens/</guid>
      <description>As a 7th grader who had just had a falling out with my social group, getting into a petty fight with a best friend, I suddenly had a large amount of free time which I spent gaming and exploring the internet. Looking for inspiration for a higher purpose and seeking out a worldview, I took to YouTube mostly. I had gotten there by watching Call of Duty videos, and then the sketch comedy channels of 2010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Age of the Internet</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/theinternet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/theinternet/</guid>
      <description>I was a really bored kid who had an easy time in school, so when I got home, what I would do was basically educate myself on youtube for eternity. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t watch those crash course history videos or anything, but rather things that I just found interesting. It started with atheism and I would juts binge watch every single video I could find on Christopher Hitchens. I still do those sort of things, when I hear a name or some celebrity I go through like every video on YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Interview Final Round Experience</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/update/</guid>
      <description>I prepared quite a bit for the MS interview - studying at least 100 LC questions and I chose to do the coding in C++. I saw so many interview questions and did so many hacker-ranks/interviews that the MS interview wasn&amp;rsquo;t too difficult. I was prepared for it and had a list of questions I wanted to ask as well - I asked If there is anything frustrating about working there, what the most successful team members do that separates them, challenges in their department and a few business-type questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SWE at Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/career/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 15:55:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/career/</guid>
      <description>The next chapter of my life will be spent as a SWE at Microsoft - I just signed the offer! Maybe it is just a feeling, but the last year or so was me taking some hard L&amp;rsquo;s (losses) - just take my word for it. I know that this is just life, but I have been down for a while now and it&amp;rsquo;s cool to see that in spite of this, my hard work has payed off .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking up</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/breakup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/breakup/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s nothing worse than a relationship on its last leg and that&amp;rsquo;s kind of where I have been for the last 3 months. It was miserable, but last night I felt like a weight was lifted off me and that I could finally breathe easy again. With so many rules, forbidden topics, and arguments/accusations, it was starting to feel like an adverserial game .
Like, we weren&amp;rsquo;t on the same team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/programming/evolutionary-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/programming/evolutionary-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Last night, for my neural networks class, we were told to make Tux (basically mario but a penguin) complete all the levels using a gradient free method. It was interesting because it was fine tuning a model that was able to get decently far into the level.
In my previous model I used convolutional neural network to feed into the features of a GRU Recurrent network. Then, without needing backprop, I trained 20 models using some small deviation on the parameters, and generated rewards for each of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 01:19:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Currently, I am a student at The University of Texas at Austin and am majoring in Computer Science. My expertise is in Cloud Computing and Software Engineering (Applications/Backend). I am excellent at C++, Java and Go. I have done a lot of coding in Python as well for artificial intelligence related courses
Other interests include food, cooking, writing, podcasts and extreme ferret racing! One thing I want to do before I die is travel to Italy or spend a day with Karl Pilkington.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complexity: What Excites Me</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/thegame/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 23:49:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/thegame/</guid>
      <description>The Game Begat the Player
With any discipline, challenge, or complexity - a difficult game always excites the clever player who tries to bend the rules in his favor. It&amp;rsquo;s a cat and mouse game where people try to gain a competitive advantage over one and other . The ingenuinity and creativity of hackers, startups, poker players and of people in dating, politics and gaming, always impresses me. People push things forward for its own sake - it&amp;rsquo;s just fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hashing</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/hashing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 20:55:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/hashing/</guid>
      <description>Cmu hashing notes
Separate Chaining  The idea is to maintain an array of linked lists All keys that hash to the same loc are just added to the linked list. Could maybe optimize these linked lists by having an lru cache implemntation or another data structure .. Cost of these operations is related to the average len of a chain. Disadvantage - costly allocation, and memory for the pointers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes notes</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 20:55:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes github guide
Ch1 Kubelet ensures containers are running and healthy
PODS  multiple containers and storage vols One deployment multiple pods containers in the same pod has access to shared volume pods are up and running until a controller destroys them needs persistent storage they are ephemeral
Deployments Blueprint is a blueprint that deploys pods according to some spec
 Sort of like an instance of a pod</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ray Tracing/Physics</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/light_physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 20:55:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/light_physics/</guid>
      <description>Mirrors
Why do mirrors reflect: Nature of the metal  Electrons are loosely attached to metals and are able to For visible light (low frequency), the electrons can match the speed and reflect the light. For UV, it is too high so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t reflect
 Different metals reflect different wavelengths The highest frequency light reflected is called plasma frequency
 This differs between metals, steel is high
  &amp;ldquo;Mirrors reflect mainly bc they are electrically conductive&amp;rdquo;  When it hits a mirror the metal cancels out the electric field parallel to the mirror, so it changes directions and reflects away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Closer Look into the Big-Four</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/big4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/big4/</guid>
      <description>Intro As a soon-to-be new grad, I am currently preparing for interviews with Google and Microsoft so I want to dive deeper into Microsoft, Google, Amazon, and Facebook.
I read the go-to book on investing and the history of the stock market about three years ago and have identified myself as a risky investor . Nothing ventured nothing gained right? His advice is that the best you can ever do is to just throw your hands up in resignment and throw your money in an low-cost index fund; he&amp;rsquo;s probably right but I like taking a risk and putting my money in companies I believe in</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issues With Go</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/issueswithgo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 15:55:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/issueswithgo/</guid>
      <description>Look at this code snippet! This is pretty standard actually - I have written code extremely similar to this. Go has no exceptions and it leads to a very ugly style of programming sometimes. Go also lacks immutables, inheritance and generics. Its dependency management is a mess (no versioning support, yes really), it has a really annoying compile time error when you have an unused import, and GOPATH takes some getting use to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Year plan</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/goals/</guid>
      <description>In 5 years I see myself working for a large tech company like Amazon/Google/Microsoft and building my skills to become an integral and useful developer. I have found that I get happiness when I see personal growth and by being ambitious/useful.
I plan on getting a few certificates and eventually doing an online masters program in the next 5 years. Building my github portfolio more is something I want to do more out of college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happiness</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/happiness/</guid>
      <description>Happiness, in my opinion, is what you feel after success in wherever your ambitions lie. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t come after being stagnant and complacent, but rather it comes after you overcome hardship. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I am especially happy yet, but I know that I am happier than I have been in 2-3 years. I have part of my life figured out - relationship and job-wise.
Technology-wise I will be happy once I become proficient in Javascript with a few projects and also finish a medium-sized project I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking of in C++.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Be a Hater</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/judging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/judging/</guid>
      <description>I watched a Vice documentary on an infamous character in American culture, and it was one of those moments where you realize you had been totally wrong about someone. The editing and narrative by Vice, was obviously trying to show a different perspective on this guy, and by the end of it the reporter seemed charmed with him and maaaybbeee had a crush on him as well
One of the top YouTube comments was &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s like someone from twitch chat became a millionaire&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 15:55:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>What I hope to get out of this blog, is a central store for my life, career and interests. Some may not care much about my career, so I intend to have other content on here as well. I have created two blogs in the past on Wordpress, but they haven&amp;rsquo;t really given me what I wanted
Putting my thoughts and projects out there seems like a cool way to connect with people!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/quotes/</guid>
      <description>If small holes aren&amp;rsquo;t fixed, then big holes will bring hardship.
It&amp;rsquo;s better to walk thousands of miles than to read thousands of books.
Every step makes a footprint.
Today&amp;rsquo;s scientists have substituted mathematics for experiments, and they wander off through equation after equation, and eventually build a structure which has no relation to reality. - Nikola Tesla
With ideas it is like with dizzy heights you climb: At first they cause you discomfort and you are anxious to get down, distrustful of your own powers; but soon the remoteness of the turmoil of life and the inspiring influence of the altitude calm your blood; your step gets firm and sure and you begin to look - for dizzier heights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re: Exit Through The Gift Shop</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/banksy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/banksy/</guid>
      <description>I just watched Exit Through The Gift Shop (2010) the other night and it has to be my favorite documentary. It&amp;rsquo;s about graffiti art and produced by Banksy. It&amp;rsquo;s a documentary started by a crazy but hilarious french cameraman, Thierry, but eventually finished by Banksy, the most famous and unmasked graffiti artist alive. Thierry, the cameraman, could never finish because he had collected thousands of hours of film over 8 years, with no real plan or storyline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/programming/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/programming/intro/</guid>
      <description>This will be a blog about things I am programming, opinions on programming languages, algorithms/projects that inspire me, and my classes as a CS undergrad at UT Austin!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threads and Processes</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/threadsprocess/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/threadsprocess/</guid>
      <description>Process is an executing program
A process can consist of multiple threads
Threads are lightweight processes used to complete small tasks; processes used for heavier tasks.
Advantages of Threads:  Lightweight Can read and write to the same data structures and resources.  Disadvantages of Threads:  IPC is difficult and errors arise Synchronization and race conditions Requires careful attention; must use a lock to prevent other threads from running a certain critical section  Advantages of Process  Independent of each other (threads are interdepedent)  Context Switching  The process of storing an d restoring context of a program so that the exectuion can be resumed from the same point at another time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GraphQL notes</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/graphql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/graphql/</guid>
      <description>GRAPHQL BASICS  It is a query language to avoid under and overfetching from apis. Most applications today have the need to fetch data from a server where that data is stored in a database. It’s the responsibility of the API to provide an interface to the stored data that fits an application’s needs. &amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo; Increased mobile usage, low-powered devices and sloppy networks were the initial reasons why Facebook developed GraphQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KubePlus notes Pt. 1</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/kubeplus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/kubeplus/</guid>
      <description>KubePlus * CaaS avoids vendor lock-in * advanced capabilities of containerized elements not possible * Kubeplus extends kubernetes with operators, different than PaaS approach * Operators extend Kubernetes API to manage software for queues, databases. Self-assemble these * Devops constructs custom PaaS, provisions, .yamls * Application Developer declares and creates application platforms as code leveraging custom resources introduced by the installed Operators.? So to find credentials the app developer may want to go and discover Postgres instances, he logs in and interacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KubePlus notes Pt. 2</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/kubeplus-pac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/notes/kubeplus-pac/</guid>
      <description>What is CloudArk? CloudArk is an API Management software , aiming to get Operators enterprise-ready. The vision is an open marketplace where companies can build their platform using a declarative format. CloudFormation, at Amazon, has grown to be highly useful because it provisions infrastructure using a single yaml file. Infrastructure-as-code. However one of the major drawbacks is vendor lock-in obviously. Enterprises want flexibility when planning for the future. Furthermore, it provisions only AWS services, limiting it significantly to the products that Amazon has built or chooses to build.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/portfolio/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>