<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal Blog on Daniel Moore&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal Blog on Daniel Moore&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Nights Short Mornings is actually a good movie</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/longnightsshortmornings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/longnightsshortmornings/</guid>
      <description>You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t think that from glancing at the imdb page, where it has a rating of 5.4&amp;frasl;10, but watching it again last night, it finally resonated with me.
I think that I watched it with my now, ex-girlfriend about a year and a half ago. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been paying close attention, and watching a movie with someone else is always a bit distracting for me. And so I came away with it empty handed and just lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hitchens</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/hitchens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/hitchens/</guid>
      <description>As a 7th grader who had just had a falling out with my social group, getting into a petty fight with a best friend, I suddenly had a large amount of free time which I spent gaming and exploring the internet. Looking for inspiration for a higher purpose and seeking out a worldview, I took to YouTube mostly. I had gotten there by watching Call of Duty videos, and then the sketch comedy channels of 2010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Age of the Internet</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/theinternet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/theinternet/</guid>
      <description>I was a really bored kid who had an easy time in school, so when I got home, what I would do was basically educate myself on youtube for eternity. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t watch those crash course history videos or anything, but rather things that I just found interesting. It started with atheism and I would juts binge watch every single video I could find on Christopher Hitchens. I still do those sort of things, when I hear a name or some celebrity I go through like every video on YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Interview Final Round Experience</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/update/</guid>
      <description>I prepared quite a bit for the MS interview - studying at least 100 LC questions and I chose to do the coding in C++. I saw so many interview questions and did so many hacker-ranks/interviews that the MS interview wasn&amp;rsquo;t too difficult. I was prepared for it and had a list of questions I wanted to ask as well - I asked If there is anything frustrating about working there, what the most successful team members do that separates them, challenges in their department and a few business-type questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking up</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/breakup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/breakup/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s nothing worse than a relationship on its last leg and that&amp;rsquo;s kind of where I have been for the last 3 months. It was miserable, but last night I felt like a weight was lifted off me and that I could finally breathe easy again. With so many rules, forbidden topics, and arguments/accusations, it was starting to feel like an adverserial game .
Like, we weren&amp;rsquo;t on the same team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complexity: What Excites Me</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/thegame/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 23:49:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/thegame/</guid>
      <description>The Game Begat the Player
With any discipline, challenge, or complexity - a difficult game always excites the clever player who tries to bend the rules in his favor. It&amp;rsquo;s a cat and mouse game where people try to gain a competitive advantage over one and other . The ingenuinity and creativity of hackers, startups, poker players and of people in dating, politics and gaming, always impresses me. People push things forward for its own sake - it&amp;rsquo;s just fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Closer Look into the Big-Four</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/big4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/big4/</guid>
      <description>Intro As a soon-to-be new grad, I am currently preparing for interviews with Google and Microsoft so I want to dive deeper into Microsoft, Google, Amazon, and Facebook.
I read the go-to book on investing and the history of the stock market about three years ago and have identified myself as a risky investor . Nothing ventured nothing gained right? His advice is that the best you can ever do is to just throw your hands up in resignment and throw your money in an low-cost index fund; he&amp;rsquo;s probably right but I like taking a risk and putting my money in companies I believe in</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Year plan</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/goals/</guid>
      <description>In 5 years I see myself working for a large tech company like Amazon/Google/Microsoft and building my skills to become an integral and useful developer. I have found that I get happiness when I see personal growth and by being ambitious/useful.
I plan on getting a few certificates and eventually doing an online masters program in the next 5 years. Building my github portfolio more is something I want to do more out of college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happiness</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/happiness/</guid>
      <description>Happiness, in my opinion, is what you feel after success in wherever your ambitions lie. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t come after being stagnant and complacent, but rather it comes after you overcome hardship. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I am especially happy yet, but I know that I am happier than I have been in 2-3 years. I have part of my life figured out - relationship and job-wise.
Technology-wise I will be happy once I become proficient in Javascript with a few projects and also finish a medium-sized project I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking of in C++.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Be a Hater</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/judging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/judging/</guid>
      <description>I watched a Vice documentary on an infamous character in American culture, and it was one of those moments where you realize you had been totally wrong about someone. The editing and narrative by Vice, was obviously trying to show a different perspective on this guy, and by the end of it the reporter seemed charmed with him and maaaybbeee had a crush on him as well
One of the top YouTube comments was &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s like someone from twitch chat became a millionaire&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re: Exit Through The Gift Shop</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/banksy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/personal/banksy/</guid>
      <description>I just watched Exit Through The Gift Shop (2010) the other night and it has to be my favorite documentary. It&amp;rsquo;s about graffiti art and produced by Banksy. It&amp;rsquo;s a documentary started by a crazy but hilarious french cameraman, Thierry, but eventually finished by Banksy, the most famous and unmasked graffiti artist alive. Thierry, the cameraman, could never finish because he had collected thousands of hours of film over 8 years, with no real plan or storyline.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>