<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Daniel Moore&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Daniel Moore&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:14:09 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://danielpygo.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Year plan</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/blog/future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:14:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/blog/future/</guid>
      <description>In 5 years I see myself working for a large tech company like Amazon/Google/Microsoft and building my skills to become an integral and useful developer. I have found that I get happiness when I see personal growth and by being ambitious/useful.  I plan on getting a few certificates and eventually doing an online masters program in the next 5 years. Building my github portfolio more is something I want to do more out of college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Game</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/blog/thegame/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 23:49:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/blog/thegame/</guid>
      <description>The Game Begat the Player  With any discipline, challenge, or complexity - a difficult game always excites the clever player who tries to bend the rules in his favor. A cat and mouse game where humans try to gain a competitive advantage over one and other. The ingenuinity and creativity of hackers, startups, poker players and of people in dating, politics and gaming, never ceases to excite me. People push things forward for its own sake - it&#39;s just fun - there is no system or paradigm that isn&#39;t constantly shifting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re: Exit Through The Gift Shop</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/blog/banksy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 16:18:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/blog/banksy/</guid>
      <description>I just watched Exit Through The Gift Shop (2010) the other night and it has to be my favorite documentary. It&#39;s about graffiti art and produced by Banksy. It&#39;s a documentary started by a crazy but hilarious french graffiti cameraman Thierry, but eventually finished by Banksy, the most famous and unmasked graffiti artist alive. Thierry, the cameraman, could never finish because he had collected thousands of hours of film over 8 years, with no real plan or storyline.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>