<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Daniel Moore&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Daniel Moore&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 15:55:32 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SWE at Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/career/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 15:55:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/career/</guid>
      <description>The next chapter of my life will be spent as a SWE at Microsoft. Maybe it is just a feeling, but the last year or so was me taking some hard L&amp;rsquo;s (losses) - just take my word for it. I know that this is just life, but I have been down for a while now and it&amp;rsquo;s cool to see that in spite of this, my hard work has payed off .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 15:55:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>What I hope to get out of this blog, is a central store for my life, career and interests. Some may not care much about my career, so I intend to have other content on here as well. I have created two blogs in the past on wordpress, but they haven&amp;rsquo;t really given me what I wanted
Putting my thoughts and projects out there seems like a cool way to connect with people!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Issues With Go</title>
      <link>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/issueswithgo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 15:55:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielpygo.github.io/posts/issueswithgo/</guid>
      <description>Look at this code snippet! This is pretty standard actually. Go has no exceptions and it leads to a very ugly style of programming sometimes. Go also lacks immutables, inheritance and generics. Its dependency management is a mess (no versioning support, yes really), it has a really annoying compile time error when you have an unused import, and GOPATH takes some getting use to. But by and large Go has been a successful language and I think it is because it makes grandiose promises of concurrency.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>